A Guide to the Papers of William Faulkner, 1917-1946
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of William Faulkner, 1917-1946
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9817-b
35 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposit of Jill Faulkner Summers, 1974.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the manuscripts for the following poems and short stories: Old ace, Dead dancer, Continuous performance, The husbandman [A green bough], L'apres-midi d'un faune, The lilacs, Music dying languidly in darkness, and One way to catch a horse, as well as untitled fragments and a brief outline for parts of Sanctuary. The collection also contains several sketches including a Japanese woman, soldiers and an airplane; and Landing in luck, as printed in the Oxford Eagle (Miss.) in 1919.
Arrangement
The collection is in two series: I. Manuscripts. II. Miscellaneous
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - Poems, This girl, she is dead, is dead,ca. 1917-1918, AMss (1 p. on 1 l.; 2 p. on 1 l.)
  - Variants on The Ace
    - Poem, The Ace,ca. 1918, AMS (1 p. on 1 l.)
    - Poem, Old Ace,n.d., TMS (3 p. on 1 l.)
    - Poem, A Dead Dancer,ca. 1918, AMss (1 p. on 1 l.; 2 p. on 2 l.)
  - Variants on L'Apres-Midi d'un Faune
    - Poem, L'Apres-Midi d'un Faune,ca. 1918, TMs with holograph additions (1 p. on 1 l.)
    - Poem, I follow her through singing trees,n.d., AMss, two drafts (1 p. on 1 l.; 1 p. on 1 l.)
    - Poem, Shakes down her blown and vagrant hair from L'Apres-Midi d'un Faune, bearing on one page a simple sketch of the torso of a male figure wearing a hat, n.d., AMs fragment (2 p. on 1 l.)
  - Poem, Hank Cadwalader....1919, TMS (1 p. on 1 l.)
  - Variants on The Lilacs
    - Poem, The Lilacs, to A...and H...,Royal Air Force,1925 August, TMs (carbon copy) (5 p. on 5 l.)
    - Poem, The Lilacs,n.d., AMs (3 p. on 3 l.)
    - Third verse of poem, The Lilacs,n.d., AMs fragment (2 p. on 1 l.)
  - Poem, The Husbandman,194[2]November 11, TMs (1 p. on 1 l.)
  - Film story snyopsis, Continuous Performance.... 1946?, TMsS fragment (38 p. on 38 l.)
  - Film story synopsis, One Way to Catch a Horse (Story line suggested by 'Norfleet')1946?, TMs(6 p. on 6 l.)
  - Poem, Music dying languidly in darkness,n.d., AMs(1 p. on 1 l.)
  - Outline for Acts I-IV of Sanctuary,n.d., AN(1 p. on 1 l.)
- Miscellaneous
  - Ten drawings
    - Three views of a Japanese woman (head, full length smelling flowers, and full length from back) n.d., (2 p. on 1 l.)
    - Sketch executed in brown pencil on blue-lined notebook paper entitle C.O.'s parade 4.S of A. RAFn.d., (1 p. on 1 l.)
    - Five sketches executed in blue pencil of soldiers, each on a sheet of blue-lined notebook paper, and one of an airplane being started, (6 p. on 6 l.)